♪ In the not
Too distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
From you or me ♪
♪ He worked
At Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
In a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
Cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his boss didn't like him
So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find
La, la, la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies begin
Or end ♪
♪ Because he used
Those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cam-bot ♪
-♪ Gypsy ♪
-Hi, girl.
-♪ Tom Servo ♪
-All good.
♪ Crow! ♪
♪ If you're wondering
How he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts
La, la, la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery
Science Theater 3000 ♪
All right now, bring it down.
Bring it down and back up again.
Back up.
Good. Hey, Cam-bot,
bring it in a little bit. Wow.
[Intercom] Thirty seconds
to commercial sign.
Wow, well it's really good
to see you again.
As you can see, we've done a lot
to change the ship
and now we're working on
Tom Servo's voice
so there's
really a lot going on.
And I have a terrible toothache.
Ow!
Uh, he's a robot.
He doesn't have any teeth,
but don't tell him.
Huh? What?
[Intercom]
Commercial sign in ten seconds.
Anyway, I'm really glad
you're here, so stick around.
[Intercom]
Commercial sign in five,
four, three, two, one.
Commercial sign out.
See ya.
[theme music playing]
Uh, don't use Novocain.
It dulls the senses.
-Okay, get ready. Open.
-Mm-mm.
-Let's go. Come on, open it up.
-Okay. Ahh...
-[drilling]
-Ah, ah, ah, ah!
That's okay. I got it. Here.
Okay.
-[drilling]
-Ah, ah, ah!
Oh, we're back. Hey, Cam-bot,
push it back a little bit.
So much has been going--
you can let go of him.
So much has been
going on on the ship,
but the biggest thing
is Tom Servo's new voice.
We're just about
to show it to you.
[drilling]
All right, give her a rip, Tom.
Let's see how it sounds.
Warning, danger, danger,
Will Robinson. Warning.
Wait, hold, hold, hold it.
I don't think--
I don't think
it's quite there yet, okay.
[drilling]
Okay, there. Give it a shot.
[Tom] [singing]
♪ Daisy, Daisy ♪
-♪ Give me your... ♪
-No, that's not quite it.
Okay. Here we got it.
[drilling]
There we go. That-- Here it is.
Hello, world. Ha!
Happy birthday! Ha ha ha!
What do you think?
Pretty neat, huh?
Oh, it's a world of difference.
You know, Joel, I'm just finally
realizing I've been to paradise,
but I've never been to me.
[laughing]
Oh, look sharp you goons.
It's the dark overlord.
Hi. Welcome to Deep 13.
Would you like to try our
smooth, creamy thruster buster?
Where's Dr. Earhart
and Dr. Forrester?
I'm Frank. I'm new here.
As for Dr. Forrester,
he stepped out for a moment.
As for Dr. Earhart...
he's missing.
[Everybody] Oh.
But as far as you
space monkeys are concerned,
I'm the new marshal in town.
That's right.
I'm the God. I'm the God!
May I take your order, please.
[chuckling]
Yeah,
what's in a thruster buster?
Uh, thruster buster is a thick,
four-pound slice of our
oven tempered meal food,
covered with wet runny
blister of growth compost,
onions, lettuce,
mayonnaise, tomatoes,
special sauce,
skanked while you sleep.
Would you like
some fries with that?
Uh, no.
We'll have,
uh, four solar burgers
and a four space buds.
Uh, would you like something
to drink with that?
Uh, yeah, uh,
what do you guys want to drink?
Uh, I'll have a splunky, mango.
Uh, cream splunky for me,
please.
Mix.
Okay, I'll have a mango, too.
Okay,
so that's four solar burgers,
four space buds,
uh, four splunkies,
two mango,
one mix and one cream.
Uh, are you going
to be eating out
or will you be
dining in with us?
Uh, what the heck?
We'll eat in.
Bring us down to Earth.
That's the button
on the left over there.
Got it. Oh, Jerry, listen,
I need you right away.
Set up four...
a table for four, okay?
Thanks, a lot.
Uh, Sylvia, I need you to take
these thruster busters
to this address right here.
Listen, no burrowing up through
the bedrooms this time, okay?
Thanks.
How's our new enterprise going?
Sold another one.
-Oh.
-That's right.
Uh, just sold our first order
to dine in as a matter of fact.
Uh, Frank. Frank, look at me
when I'm talking to you.
We don't do dine in.
We only do take out.
Who wants to dine in anyway?
Oh, it's, uh...
it's Joel and the robots.
I was just about
to bring them down.
What? No!
Uh-oh. Looks like the splunky's
about to hit the fan.
-There.
-Oh! Owie! Owie! Owie! Owie!
Frank, go get this
week's invention exchange.
And as for you,
my takeout troglodyte,
the only thing you're going
to be served is more bad movies.
Now I know Frank isn't much,
but he's showing a lot of
promise in the invention area,
and I don't think you're going
to be able to put one over on us
this week,
but you go ahead, Joel.
Hit me with your best shot.
Fire away.
Hey, sirs, what do you think?
It's my new invention.
Back it up, Cam-bot.
It's called the BGC19.
And it's based on the premise
that drummers just don't get
enough attention
way in the back.
With the BGC19, you can supply
that all-important backbeat.
[drums playing]
And still walk around
and be a dynamic front man
at the same time.
Now what's your invention?
That's it. That's it.
That's good.
That's right. Thanks.
Well, it's called the BGC19.
It's based on the premise that
most drummers being in the back
don't get enough attention.
-Frank.
-Hmm?
-There!
-Oh! Owie! Owie! Owie!
I didn't know
it's wrong to steal!
Who are you to judge?
Well, Joel,
under the circumstances,
I'm afraid I'm going to have
to stick it to you this week.
Rocketship X-M will assault
your pop and folk sensibilities.
It's a chillingly uninteresting
assault of mind-numbing,
gut-wrenching,
brain-bloating non-action.
Oh, Lloyd Bridges movie?
I guess I could handle that.
Uh, Lloyd Bridges
with Hugh O'Brian?
-[yells] No! And movie siren!
-[alarm blaring]
[music playing]
[Tom]
Robert L. Lippert presents...
[Joel] Hey, I showed
them the BGC19.
I think they really liked it.
-[Crow] Cool.
-[Joel] There's a new guy...
that new guy stole it.
-[Tom] Oh, look.
-[Crow] Lloyd Bridges?
By this time, his lungs
would be aching for air.
[Tom and Crow laugh]
[Joel] Hey, "Huge" O'Brian.
[Tom humming music]
[Tom] Ready? Here we go.
[all singing] ♪ Don't get
Your hopes up too high ♪
♪ Because when it's
All said and done ♪
♪ It's a Lloyd Bridges movie ♪
♪ If you're looking
for something good ♪
♪ Then an hour from now,
you're going to be weeping ♪
[music continues playing]
[Joel] Communism
by Clarence Marks.
[Tom] Ice cream by Frank Heath.
[Crow] Gas by Betty Sinclair.
[Tom] Cowboy hats
by Clarence Steensen.
[Joel] Financed by Don Cash.
[Crow] Vibes by Orville Hampton.
[Joel] Chapstick by Mary Chaffee
[Crow] Stupid name
by Ferde Grofe guy.
[Tom] Oh, Murray,
the ceiling needs painting.
[music continues playing]
[Tom] Kind of cheery, isn't it?
[Tom] Hmm.
[Joel] Well, that guy's
trespassing right there.
[Crow] Hmm.
[Joel] Yeah, what's he
trying to prove anyway?
Smart guy.
[Tom] Let him carry watches.
[Crow] Hey, Petey, I'll race ya.
[car sounds]
[Joel] Marry me, Steve.
[Crow] Well, your lifeline shows
you'll meet four interesting...
[Tom] Now wrap it
around her neck.
[Joel] Either this man is dead
or my watch has stopped.
[chuckles]
[Crow] So not as good as us,
is he? [chuckles]
Nothing to be alarmed about.
Quite understandable
under the circumstance.
The weaker sex.
The only one whose
blood pressure is normal.
[Joel] Good one, Lloyd.
[PA] X minus 17 minutes.
We're due in the assembly hall
in another minute.
[Crow] Assembly today?
That means no class. Hurray.
Thank you, doctor,
and good night.
[Joel] So who's for ribs?
[Tom] Going down to Rudy's?
I'm going to the market, maybe.
Get some onion rings.
Want a full loaf?
I think I can handle it.
[Joel] I'm going to get some
for my wife.
[Tom] I'm gonna phone ahead.
-[chatter]
-Good stuff. I like it.
-I ordered some for my wife.
-[Crow] Rhubarb, rhubarb.
Scientific rhubarb.
[Crow] And now, the cast of
I Married Four Astronauts.
[Joel] You know,
we think we can take 'em.
[PA] X minus 16 minutes.
[Tom] In a few minutes, I'll be
cutting these people open.
[Crow] Our panel tonight
will be Robert Q. Lewis,
Kitty Carlisle, Arleen Francis
and Dorothy Kil...
Uh, no, I'm sorry. Dorothy
won't be appearing tonight.
Ladies and gentlemen.
[Joel] Our first structure
is called tag.
Every news service and newspaper
is represented here tonight.
[Tom]
All 12 newspapers in the world.
For your cooperation in the past
when complete secrecy was vital,
we are grateful.
[Crow]
Thank you for being gutless.
However, I must make
something clear.
[Tom] I'm wearing a bra.
Although ours is not strictly
a military project,
a great deal of our research
and knowledge
falls within
security regulations.
Therefore, I must insist
that you reveal
only such information
as appears
in the authorized press release,
which will be
handed to you later.
[Joel] Young Republicans are
in the back handing them out.
I'm sure that we can
all recall the wild tales
of the flying disks,
flying saucers, space ships.
[Joel] Frisbees,
weather balloons...
And who knows
what imaginative creations.
The press is to be commended for
discounting in most instances
these premature rumors.
And so helping to minimize
public apprehension.
Tonight, you are invited here
to witness an important event.
[Joel] My outing.
You are all familiar with
our previous work in sending
robot missiles into space.
That phase is at an end.
[Crow] I killed it,
and I'm glad.
Tonight we will launch
the first manned space ship.
[Tom] Then we love.
The RXM.
Rocketship Expedition Moon.
[PA] X minus 13 minutes.
[Joel]
Hey, do you have a pencil?
[Crow]
Does expedition start with an x?
...dreamed of visiting
the nearest of heavenly bodies.
Some for adventurous
fantastic reasons,
others like ourselves because
they... visualize
the successful lunar expedition.
[Crow] Others to get chicks.
As the first step toward
practical interplanetary travel.
Today there is even
the possibility
that an unassailable base
could be established on the moon
to control world peace.
[Joel] Our kind of world peace.
[Fleming] I will now
introduce to you
the head of this expedition
and his crew.
[Tom] He's a widower who enjoys
long walks on the beach
and parasailing.
[Fleming] Designer of the RXM,
and as you all know,
one of the most brilliant
physicists of the day
and an old friend.
-Dr. Lisa Van Horn...
-[Tom] Rooty toot toot.
[Fleming] ...his most abled
coworker and assistant,
doctor of chemistry...
[all] And a good friend.
[Fleming] Floyd Graham, pilot.
[all] And an old friend.
[Fleming] Mr. Harry Chamberlain,
astronomer of the Mount Wilson
and Palomar Observatory.
[Joel] Dirk Square jaw.
[Fleming] Mr. Chamberlain
will serve as navigator.
[Crow] I never liked him.
[Fleming] Major
William Corrigan, engineer.
[Tom] Comic relief.
[Fleming] I shall now
ask Dr. Eckstrom
to outline
the flight plan for you.
-Carl?
-[Crow clapping]
[Crow] Uh, thank you darling...
I mean, Larry.
[PA] X minus 14 minutes.
[Tom] Oh, no hurry.
[Joel] Now Rommel
will be at base camp here.
The distance between
the Earth and the moon
at its closest proximity
is 238,000 miles.
[Joel] Neat, huh?
We expect to cover this distance
in approximately 48 hours.
[Crow] New York Times
spit your gum out.
...will be the ascent
to an altitude of 300 miles.
From the start while we
pass through the troposphere
and stratosphere
until we reach the ionosphere,
the flight will be controlled
by our automatic pilot.
[Joel] Named Timmy.
[Dr. Eckstrom] After we have
climbed through the atmosphere,
we will turn the rocket
into a parallel course
with the surface of the Earth.
In flying parallel
with the Earth's surface,
we receive added boosts
from its rotation.
[Crow] And we'll be collecting
bonus coins and mushrooms...
[PA] X minus 13 minutes.
[Tom] We baked a rocket earlier
in a 450-degree oven.
The RXM is what is known as
a multistage or step rocket.
[Joel] At this point,
the rocket becomes engorged
with astronauts.
...will be jettison.
The nose section, which is
a complete rocket containing
enough fuel for the entire trip
and also containing our cabin,
overcomes the gravitational pull
of the Earth
and heads in the direction
of the moon.
[Joel] Then we stop
for a quick snack.
After we have passed
the equilibrium point,
where the Earth and the moon's
gravities are in balance,
we will reduce power
to a minimum.
The moon's attraction will
carry us the rest of the way.
[Tom] With the grace of God
and a long-handled spoon.
Finally, we will reverse
the rocket,
utilizing the thrust of its
motors to make our landing.
[Crow] Uh, could you repeat
that part about the moon?
A few more details
which might interest you.
The cabin is pressurized
and gyro controlled
keeping us in a level position
at all times.
We carry radar for navigation,
short wave for communication.
[Joel] Eight tracks
and cassettes in stereo.
...more than twice the amount
of fuel we expect to use
to keep well within
the margin of safety.
[Crow] Like most
American vehicles.
[PA] X minus 12 minutes.
[Tom] Thank you, God.
We still have a few moments,
ladies and gentlemen,
for questions
if any of you care to...
[Tom] The laser breast exam
is on Friday,
and remember
I'll be in my office Tuesday,
but not Wednesday.
[theme music playing]
Chamberlain...
how do you fit into the picture?
Do you...
do you have any family?
[Crow] Not that I know of.
I've been living
on mountaintops.
I'm afraid it's too lonely
for such opportunities.
-Have you ever done any flying?
-[Joel] Oh, yeah.
But you're the navigator.
You must realize that intersolar
flight requires far more exact
and precise navigation
than any earthbound voyage.
-Um-hmm.
-Plus that's incidental.
-It is?
-Yes.
You see, as an astronomer,
I can appreciate the perfect
observation conditions
on a body without atmosphere.
-[Tom] And you can't.
-Such is our moon.
Do you realize
that within one hour...
I got about 800 head
grazing down there.
[Joel]
That's a whole lot of head.
I bought my ranch with
the flight pay I saved up
-during the war.
-Um-hmm.
How does your wife feel
about you going?
Well, she's a Texan, too.
[Joel] That means
she's rock stupid.
She knows that when a Texas man
makes up his mind
to do something, that's it.
Period. [laughs]
I wish you fellows
could have seen her face
so when I walked in and told her
in the strictest confidence,
of course,
"Honey, I'm going to the moon."
-What did she say?
-[Joel] Not tonight, dear.
I've got a headache.
[William] She looked at me
for a second
and then said, "What for?
They ain't got nothing there
that we don't have more of
-right here in Texas."
-[laughing]
[Crow] But of course,
by that time
our lungs were aching for air.
In the training room.
I've done more flying
this last month
than I've done
in over 100 missions.
[Tom] Uh, great.
Now about your hair.
This is the hottest crew
I have ever worked with,
especially
in the brains department.
-[all] Nice brains.
-[Tom] Attractive, too.
Hubba hubba.
Yeah, I agree.
-But you can quote me on this.
-[Joel] Oh, may I?
Unless you look like a test tube
or a chemical formula,
-you haven't got a chance.
-[Tom] And I do.
From the woman's angle,
Dr. Van Horn,
how does it feel making a trip
like this alone with four men?
[Tom] Do the words
"dream come true" ring a bell?
I never thought much about it.
Tell me, doctor, is there
any specific reason
why one member of the crew
should be a woman?
I'd like to answer that
if I may.
[Tom] Hmm.
The reason Ms. Van Horn
is making this trip is because
of her pioneering research
with monotonic hydrogen.
[Crow]
And she's cute as a button.
...develop the
first rocket fuel,
powerful and concentrated enough
to make this flight possible.
[PA] X minus 11 minutes.
[Joel] Uh, astronauts
get to the rocket.
You may view the takeoff
from the observation bunker
and return to this room
immediately afterward.
Everybody return here
after the takeoff.
[Crow]
Uh, accept the astronauts.
We need them on the rocket.
[Tom] Are you an astronaut
if you're wearing dungarees,
and you've been training
for the last two years?
[Joel] No. I can't remember.
Were we supposed to stay?
[Tom] No. I think we're
supposed to go to the rocket.
-[Tom] He said...
-[Crow] Was it this way?
[Joel] He said astronauts
straight back.
-[Crow] I'm an astronaut.
-[Tom] Wanna stop for ribs?
[Joel] Hello, Cleveland.
[PA]
X minus seven minutes.
[Tom] Oh, great.
That's the support team?
Three guys and a woody.
[Crow] Hey, I loved that movie.
[man] Gyro control
and compass are okay.
Batteries are all up,
autopilot's okay.
Everything's in order.
[Joel] Yeah, thanks for sharing.
I've checked these calculations
many times. They're correct.
[Tom] I'll be the judge of that.
[man 1] Oh yes,
all commercial flights
have been detoured
100 miles south.
[man 2] Thank you.
Well, I can't think of anything
we've overlooked.
All we need now
is a little luck.
Doesn't seem real that
the moment finally has arrived
after all these years.
It has been a long time.
A long time for
two men to work together.
-[whistling]
-[coughing]
Remember when we started,
what they called us?
-[Joel] Siegfried and Roy?
-Young crackpots.
Yes, and what are now?
-[Joel] Siegfried and Roy?
-Maybe just crackpots.
The only regret I have
is that I have to stay behind.
Your job is no less important,
Robert.
I know, but still.
-[PA] X minus six minutes.
-[Crow] We'll have Paris.
Look, you're getting on that
rocket and that's all there is.
Good luck.
[man 1] Good luck, everybody.
[Joel] Uh, can I catch
a ride to the rocket?
I'm only going to the gantry.
[Tom] Gantry?
This car don't go anywhere
near a gantry.
You boys is lost. [laughing]
Fat old dog, ain't you?
[Crow German accent]
Here in Peenemünde is where
rockets are assembled
and once the rockets go up,
who cares where they come down?
That's not my department,
you know.
[Tom, Crow, Joel] ♪ Valderi,
Valdera, Valderi, Valdera ♪
[Joel] Can I still bet
on Max Schmeling?
-[PA] X minus five minutes.
-Oh, good.
[Tom, Crow, Joel] ♪ Valderi,
Valdera, Valderi, Valdera ♪
[Tom] Well, five minutes to go.
There's no rush,
as long as they're close.
I mean,
this ain't rocket science.
[Dr. Eckstrom]
Take one more look.
[Tom spitting]
You won't be as close as this
to mother Earth for some time.
-[Crow] Just get on the rocket!
-[Joel] Come on.
Hey, look. It looks like an
Al Jaffee
Mad Magazine fold-in,
you know you can
fold it together.
It would probably
spell something like Ohio or...
We keep the motors inn high...
-[Crow] Huh?
-[Joel] Hm? What'd he say?
[Tom] All right, come on.
One at a time. Don't crowd.
Don't crowd.
Go on up there, Joel.
[Crow] Hey, that-- that's
what it's like to be born.
[Joel] They're coming up
through the toilet.
I'm positive, yeah.
[Tom] Close the lid.
There's a lady on board, please.
[Crow] Well...
[PA] X minus four minutes.
[Crow] Last one out of the biff
is a rotten egg.
Oh, that's you Bill.
[laughs]
I was about to cut you up
with a coat hanger.
[Tom] Call me Cobra.
[Joel] Put a new float
while I was down there.
[scoffs] Cut me up
with a coat hanger.
[Crow] Hey, that guy's
not kidding. Nag, nag, nag.
No change
of flight plans discussed.
First seven minutes of flight...
-Controlled by automatic pilot.
-Pilot's ready.
[Joel] But he has
a question for you.
Seven minutes...
straight ascent.
Straight ascent
from starting point.
Starting thrust using
all tail assembly engines,
-twenty-three hundred tons.
-Right.
[Tom] Straight, no chaser,
twist of lime.
Your mixture?
Hydrogen and oxygen plus A12.
After 120 seconds,
hydrogen and oxygen plus A14.
After 340 seconds,
hydrogen plus A16.
-After 560 seconds, A16.
-Right.
-Any questions?
-[Crow] Yeah, what's A16?
[PA] X minus two minutes.
[Tom] I resent him.
Good luck.
[Joel] I'm bushed.
I'm turning in.
[Tom] I'll do the honors,
little lady.
[Crow] Good night,
Rockford Dad.
[Joel] Good night, Mike Nelson
of Sea Hunt fame.
[Tom] Good night,
guy who looks like Mr. Whipple,
a little like Walt Disney,
maybe Mr. Mooney.
-[PA] X minus one minute.
-[Joel] Good night, oven clock.
[Tom] Good night,
guys in the bunker.
[Crow] Good night,
junior high school
custodian closet like room.
[Joel]
Did I leave the water running?
[Tom] Oh God, I need this job.
[PA] X minus 40 seconds.
[Joel] Sure hope Jimmy
brought the Camaro in.
[PA] X minus 30 seconds.
[Crow] By this time,
my lungs were aching for air.
[PA] X minus 20 seconds.
[Tom] I hope this new chin
holds out.
[PA] X minus ten seconds.
[Tom] They're at the post,
and they're off.
[PA] Three, two, one...
[Joel] Muffins are done.
[PA] Zero.
[Tom] Stock footage away.
[Crow] Hmm.
[Joel] It's great.
[Crow snoring]
[Tom] Can't zip my fly, ooh.
[Crow] By this time, my lungs...
[Joel] Buddy Ebsen
likes this ride.
[Tom] Bye. Bye.
[German accent]
Get out of my way. I can't see!
[suspenseful music playing]
[Tom] Bye.
[Tom] ♪ Valderi, Valdera,
Valderi, Valdera ♪
[Crow Well, that's a wrap.
Enjoy the buffet.
We'll attempt to establish
radio contact with the ship.
[Joel] The rest of the movie
takes place in space.
You can all go home now.
[Tom] Now they think of
radio contact.
Those are little miles.
And those are big miles.
-[Crow] Good morning.
-[yawning]
-[Joel] Morning, everybody.
-[Tom] Morning.
[Tom] Rise and shine.
The human body can
withstand these accelerations,
but it certainly
was never meant to.
[Crow] What did you expect?
You're an astronaut, Dicky.
Feel like I was just tossed
off the spooky bronc.
[Joel] I just ate my own vomit.
[Van Horn] Are you all right,
doctor?
Oh, yes. Can't hurt
an old campaigner like me.
[Tom] Unless you bang my head
into a steel grate.
Radar and gyro compass in order.
[Floyd] Automatic pilot, okay.
-Fuel consumption?
-Normal.
-[Crow] Spinach quiche?
-[Tom] Almost done.
Fifteen pounds.
[Tom] Let's go.
-We gotta get out of here.
-[Crow] Oh, yeah.
[Tom] Suppose they had a war
and nobody came.
Where do you want to be
in two years?
-We at the Satellite of Love...
-[Crow, Tom] Doom doom doom...
...take this time
to salute some of the
unsung heroes of today's film.
[Crow, Tom] The reporters
of Rocketship X-M.
-They are the unsung heroes...
-[Crow, Tom] Doom doom doom...
...that cuddle in back rooms,
nameless like so many cattle.
Uh, they are...
slightly out of focus
and we hold forth that
they should not be forgotten.
[Crow, Joel] Doom doom...
[Tom] They are the journalists,
the plucky personnel
of the press corps
whose mighty pens and pencils
dutifully record
whatever drivel they are fed.
Proud and passionate, and
blessed by the elegant beauty
of the United States
space program.
-[Crow] And so we present to you
-[Joel hums]
the journalists of
Rocketship X-M.
Um, roll them slides, Cam-bot.
[Joel] Meet correspondent
Donald Bunsen,
science editor
for the Allen Meyer Flash.
His scathing seven-part series
on stop-cocks
almost won him the
1953 Pulitzer Prize 80626.
[Tom] The famous twin reporting
team of Dirk and Kirk Berger who
-cover both sides of a story,
-[Joel humming]
Dirk upfront
and Kirk always from behind.
Their style is like
an Oreo cookie.
Hard biting reporters
on the outside,
a creamy story in between.
[Crow] On the left,
Hugh Beaumont's brother Spike,
hairstyle editor for
Today's Rugged Man.
The boys in the city room say
Spike can sniff out
an ounce of pomade
from inside a locked closet.
Notice Spike has donned
his flying winged lapel suit
in preparation
for today's plumb assignment,
the trendsetting hair helmet
of Lloyd Bridges.
[Joel] Peering over
Spike's left shoulder
is foreign affairs correspondent
for Digest Digest
Peter K. Whimple, mild-mannered
and meek to a fault
Whipple's motto is "When will it
be my turn" now 91807.
[Tom] Ladies Home Foundation
Garments is well represented
-by cub reporter Robert Bland.
-[Joel, Crow humming]
Here we see him
gathering information
for his upcoming piece
on zero gravity girdles.
Don't let that flint
hard exterior fool you.
He's wearing a Warner bra,
trimmed with delicate
peak-a-boo lace.
[Crow] Leering in from the back
is chief editor of
White Male Perspective,
Wilhelm Studman.
Visibly upset with the intrusion
of a mere girl
into a man's world.
Studman keeps his distance
because Chanel No. 5
gives him hives. [chuckles]
The boys in the press corps have
nicknamed him The Gollum.
[Joel] And there's so many more.
There's Billy, Frank, and Judy.
[Tom] Fast Talking Fanny
and Automatic Slim.
[Crow] There's Roy and Scoop
and Cold Type.
[Joel] All Man,
Mr. Peepers and The Leech.
[Tom] And this guy.
He's a Woozle.
His name is peanut.
These are the men and women
of the press corps
who will do anything
for a story.
Unless they're told
to withhold information.
[all] We salute the press corps
of Rocketship X-M.
Excelsior!
[music playing]
[Joel] What's your dream?
Harry.
-Marvelous site, isn't it?
-It is.
You study maps,
globes and try to visualize.
[Joel] Then you get up in space
and... God,
your hair smells good.
[Harry] Hard to express it.
[Dr. Eckstrom] Stand by to turn.
[Crow] Like this?
Or like that?
Like that? Okay. I got it.
[Tom] Hoist the mizzen,
Mr. Cavendish!
Knot the main sheet.
Blow me down.
-Four, three...
-[Joel] Five.
-[Dr. Eckstrom] Two. Turn
-[Joel] Twelve.
[Tom] Look smart, me ladies.
Harrr mee bonny tarrrrs.
[Crow] Weigh that anchor.
-[Tom] Yeah.
-[Crow] I can’t even lift it.
[Tom singing]
♪ Where is love? ♪
♪ Is it in the stars? ♪
[William] Ninety-degree turn
completed.
She will have a flight speed
of 3,400 miles per hour.
Altitude 360 miles.
[Van Horn] How do we stand
on fuel now?
[Crow] I'm for it.
-[Van Horn] Mixture at present.
-[William] A16.
Harry, contact the base.
[Crow] Oh, Gary, ahh.
RXM calling BWS.
Over.
[mane on radio] Come in, RXM.
Over to you.
-[Joel] No. Over to you.
-Standby BWS.
Eckstrom speaking.
[Joel] The press is
a bunch of wusses.
Are you alone in there?
[radio] And are circling the
globe at 3,400 miles per hour.
We will increase speed gradually
until we reach escape velocity
of 25,000 miles per hour.
[Joel] Oh, traffic on the I94
is heavy today...
and it seems to be jamming up
along Spaghetti Junction.
We'll be standing by.
-[Tom] Tall and proud.
-Fifty-five hundred miles.
Continue acceleration.
[Crow] Oh, bless the beast
and children.
[Tom] One tin soldier.
[Joel] Go placidly
amidst the noise and haste
and remember what comfort?
It's the Chrysler building.
Hey, what happened
to the rest of the night?
[Joel] Hey, who left his post?
If it's darkness you want,
wait until we enter outer space.
[Crow]
And then look into my soul.
Six thousand.
Six thousand two-hundred
miles per hour.
[Joel] Come on, look alive!
You're getting scale. Let's go!
Radar is tracking
them perfectly.
I had contact with them
four minutes ago.
Altitude 1600 miles,
speed 21,000 miles per hour,
constantly increasing.
They're about to reach
escape velocity.
-[Tom] I win the baby pool.
-Twenty-two thousand.
Bill, check the pressurizing
system and oxygen.
This kind of weather
makes me feel right at home.
[Crow]
You mean this musty stench.
Like a nice cool night
in East Texas.
Twenty-four thousand.
Take a reading the moment
we attain escape velocity.
-Yes, sir.
-Standby.
[Tom] Why?
Is something gonna happen?
Should we get ready
for the boring part now?
Twenty-five thousand.
Prepare to jettison
tail section.
[Tom] Oh, wow.
Start the front assembly motors.
Only 40 second
supply of fuel left.
[whistling sound]
[Crow] Oh. Was that me?
Dehydrated ice cream. Sorry.
You ready?
Ready.
Go.
Reduce power.
[Tom] Dad, stop!
We lost the camper!
Look out!
[Joel] Well, we won't
be trying that again.
That was a little
too close for comfort.
We might be in vacuum, but I
sure felt the wind of that one.
[Tom] Uh, no. That was me.
Harry, contact the base again.
[Crow] Attention, base.
Snafu big time.
Over.
[man on radio] Come in, RXM.
Over to you.
Standby BWS.
[Tom] Give me that.
We're on our way.
[man on radio] We have
jettisoned the tail section
and are now reducing
power and speed
according to plan
until we come within
the attraction of the moon.
[Joel] That's my man
up there, and yes,
I think I love him.
[man on radio]
Everybody aboard is well.
[Crow] This is Rocketship X-M
now concluding
our broadcast day.
BWS calling RXM.
Come in, RXM!
[Joel, Tom, Crow
humming "Star-Spangled Banner]
[Joel] Come on, spread out.
Give me some air.
What's the deal?
[Fleming] Ladies and gentlemen,
we had hoped by having
the entire press
represented here tonight,
to eliminate any possible
hearsay, rumor
or speculation
put in the reports.
However, I regret to have
to have to ask you to confine
yourselves to the
official news release.
[Joel] And stop ranting about...
I promise to hand you any news
that may come in
as soon as it can be cleared.
[Crow] In other words, your trip
here was a waste of time.
You could have phoned it in.
[Joel] Where do you want to be
in two years, snowflake?
Don't think
I like all this dark.
It might be all right
for sleeping,
but for a steady diet, uh-uh.
I used to hate the daylight
because I couldn't work.
Up here in this eternal night,
it's a different feeling.
A fella can get used
to anything I guess if he...
[Crow]
Yeah, once they ate woodchuck.
I remember when
I was first assigned to jets,
I said to the colonel,
"Colonel,
I join this man's Air Force
to fly an airplane,
but nobody's going to hitch me
to no Roman candle."
[Crow] And nobody's going to
strap me to a diving board naked
and face down
in a pool of marshmallow cream.
Boy oh boy.
Ain't she pretty?
[Tom] What do you see, fella?
[Joel] It says "Rand McNally"
across the top.
Do you see Texas?
No.
It's in the other hemisphere.
[Joel] Tell me your dream.
...from this distance it would
only appear a mere speck.
A mere speck?
Texas a mere speck?
Listen, my friend,
I'm broadminded.
I've been around people, but...
don't you ever let any
other Texan here you say that.
A mere speck!
[Crow] Hey, it was
just an observation.
[Joel] Uh, what's my line?
Oh, I better
check my script here.
Yeah. That's it.
[Tom] Now I swing into high
and make my move.
It's the funniest sensation.
I feel like I'm walking
on a cloud, no effort at all.
[Tom] Not for you.
We're getting deeper
into interplanetary space.
Gravity will soon be
practically nonexistent.
-[Joel] Hmm.
-Huh. We got a stowaway aboard.
[laughing]
[Crow] Ha ha ha.
-Hey, whoa.
-[Crow] I love this old jacket.
I need you.
[Tom] Hey, we really are
having fun, aren't we?
[Floyd] Don't you think
it's amusing?
Nothing funny about that.
Simply the lack of gravity.
-[Tom] She's right.
-Of course, Dr. Van Horn.
[Joel, tom, Crow laughing]
[Crow] Those straps
get me every time.
[Joel, tom, Crow laughing]
[theme music playing]
Now don't get mad at me.
But can't you ever relax?
All these weeks, months,
I've been watching you.
[Tom] Yeah, take a week off.
Well, I've been wondering.
How does a girl like you
get mixed up in a thing
like this in the first place?
[Joel] Have to stand
next to a guy like me.
I suppose you think
that women should only cook
and sew and bear children?
-[Crow snorting]
-Isn't that enough?
There's such a thing
as going overboard
in the other direction too,
you know.
-If you don't...
-[explosion]
[Tom] Hmm. What is it?
Hmm.
[Joel] Chauvinist detector
just went off.
Oh, false alarm. It's just
the dryer. It's off kilter.
I'll check the engines.
Phil, pressurize
the motor room first.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Joel] Who turned on the radio?
Would you shut that music off,
please?
Motor room pressure up.
[Crow] Uh, Houston,
we got a problem.
Lloyd's making moves
on the babe here.
[Joel] Oh man, if it's not
one thing, it's another.
Who forgot to flush?
[underwater sounding]
Wow. This is neat up here.
We can make a fork,
start her all over.
[Joel underwater] Let's see.
This thing goes into
another thing
and then comes out
somewhere over here.
[Tom mumbles underwater]
We're still drifting.
[Crow] Off to sleep.
[Joel underwater]
Well, we stared at it.
That ought to fix it.
Let's get out of here.
[Tom underwater] Okay.
After 14 hours and 12 minutes,
we covered 112,000 miles.
We'll come within
the gravitational traction
-of the moon.
-That's not important right now.
Without power, we're helplessly
suspended in space.
Even if we were already
within the gravitational reach,
we'd still be unable
to make a landing.
We need power to land.
Checked and double checked
all connections.
Primers, fuel injectors,
can't find a thing wrong.
-[Joel] Hmm.
-[Tom] Hmm. Um-hm.
It must
be the fuel mixture.
[Joel] Hmm. Possible.
-[Joel] Can't tell.
-[Tom] Yeah.
[Crow] Dear Diary,
well, we're all going to die,
and it's the men's fault.
Our fiery demise is imminent,
but at least I have my health.
Knock on wood.
Oh, I saw the cutest thing
on Arsenio last night.
How much oxygen do we carry?
Don't worry. We have
plenty left for the trip.
For the trip as planned,
you mean.
[Joel] Oh, that hurt.
[Tom humming]
[Tom] Hmm? What's this?
[Crow] Oh, great, a harmonica.
As if this guy wasn't
annoying enough?
Out with the harmonica.
[Tom chuckles]
What's next? Stories about
his uncle in Milwaukee.
[Tom] Oops.
[harmonica playing]
If you don't mind.
[Joel] Geez, what a grouch.
The differential is six over M
to the 30th power.
The halfway check result is
262,000 to 341,000
both using tangent E, correct?
[Joel] Huh? Oh, sorry.
I was drawing Bucky here.
It must be the same.
There's an error there.
I've made no error,
Dr. Eckstrom.
I have to say that you made an
error and discard your figures.
I'm sorry.
-[Tom] Sheesh.
-Don't be.
Surely, you're not going
to let emotion enter into this.
-[Tom] Oh, why would I?
-Certainly not.
We'll continue computing
using my results as a basis.
[all] Blow hard.
Except that I feel very strongly
I should say that
we should try both.
We can't.
To complete either calculation
would take six to eight hours.
We can't afford the time.
It's either one or the other,
Dr. Van Horn.
But it doesn't have to be.
You can't be arbitrary
about imposing your will
when these people's lives
are at stake.
Don't you realize that?
You speak as calmly as if
you were saying pass the salt.
Aren't you human?
Are you made of ice?
[Crow] I'm human.
Now shut up and pass the salt.
I'm sorry. I apologize.
For what?
For momentarily being a woman?
[Joel] Thank you
Mr. White male reality.
Now, shall we go ahead?
Yes, doctor.
Engine L9.
[Joel] If we make
the eyes a little bigger.
[Crow] Meanwhile, back on Earth,
silos are bursting
with nature's rich bounty.
[Tom] Mount Palomar, California,
the mighty 200-inch
reflecting Hale telescope
is lofted skyward.
Then, the eyepiece is blackened,
and an unsuspecting scientist
puts his eye to it.
-Comedy ensues.
-[phone ringing]
Sign here, Mr. Wilson.
Hello?
Yes?
It's Dr. Hurley at Mount
Palomar.
Yes, Dr. Hurley? Yes?
We located the RXM's position
at 7:16 this morning.
Since then, there has
been very little change.
[Tom] Voice of Winnie the Pooh.
[Dr. Hurley on the phone]
Apparently, their velocity
was far more
than we anticipated.
Are you sure, doctor?
[Crow] I think everyone
ought to come in
and have a hot cup of cocoa
and come inside
and be nice and snugly.
[music playing]
[Tom]
I have some rather bad news.
There's more film.
[Joel] Say, I never climbed
inside this thing.
Kind of funny in here.
[Crow] Look through the big end.
[Tom] See, it's warm.
So, hmm.
[Joel] This is what we would
have seen from the Hubble.
[Crow] So I sing you
to sleep after the lovin'.
The wind that blows
between the worlds,
cutting like a knife.
-[Tom] Um-hmm.
-[Van Horn] What?
Nothing. It's a line
from Kipling's "Tomlinson".
The poem about the chap's...
soul in a fix.
He couldn't get
into Heaven or Hell.
Suspended in space.
Would you do something for me,
please?
[Joel, Tom] Shut up?
I need those two graphs
under Dr. Eckstrom's arm.
I'm tired and shaky,
I might awaken him.
[Tom] Yeah, and then put his
arm in a pan of lukewarm water.
[snickering]
I knocked over a ten foot
Christmas tree once
while decorating
at my cousin's house
just from trying to do something
when I was too tired.
[Crow] Oh, what does this story
have to do with anything, Lloyd?
...came rushing in.
First, they thought I was
Santa Claus lying there
with a busted tinsel star
in my nose.
I spoiled everything.
[Tom] Now you tell me
that's not funny.
[Joel] He's waking up.
Quick! Tell that story again.
-Thanks.
-It's no trouble.
Why don't you take
a minute off from that?
[Crow] She's pretending to work
so she doesn't
have to talk to you.
You'll think clearer if you do.
When I was flying in the war,
we had a guy like...
-[Crow] No!
-[Tom] Brother.
-[Joel] Shut up!
-[Crow] Boo!
Too bad.
He blew his top.
We had to put him
in section eight.
Held it in too long.
Never let down a second.
[Crow] Never tasted human flesh.
You're right.
I'm not even thinking
straight anymore.
[Joel] I must be tired.
I'm almost interested
in what you're talking about.
-[Tom] Let's get outta here.
-[Joel] I'll grab you.
There we go.
[Joel] Yep. Okay.
[Tom] It's about donut shapes.
[music playing]
Now did I or did I not address
the topic of selective gravity,
Mr. Crow?
Uh, well we did global
and what's the other thing?
-I don't...
-[Tom] Shh.
Mr. Crow,
please try to pay attention.
This is for your benefit.
Yes, sir. Sorry.
All right, selective gravity is
the ease of which fish line...
Or... or wire sir?
Or wire can be attached
to an object to make it float.
Oh, like a biscuit?
We'll get to that.
Anyway, the object you're going
to be floating has to have
a high degree
for humor or levity,
just a little joke
for the TA's there.
Now, I'm going to be
floating some objects here.
Uh, with wire?
With wire, and you're going to
tell me if they're funny or not.
All right?
First, we start off with a coat.
Funny or not funny?
-[Tom] Funny?
-Right, funny.
Next, Cam-bot, bring it over
to the right here a little bit.
A wrench, funny or not funny?
[Tom] Uh, I'd say funny.
Right, funny, finally.
-A harmonica.
-Oh, oh, oh, oh!
Funny or not funny?
-[Crow] Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
-Okay, Crow, Crow.
Uh, uh... I forgot the question.
Funny or not funny?
Uh, funny.
Are you sure?
Not funny.
It was funny.
Stick to your guns, Crow.
Now I'm going to be
showing you some flashcards.
You'll be awarded 20 points
for every correct flashcard.
These are objects that
are funny or not funny
when they're floating.
All right? Start things off.
-Sand.
-Uh, not funny.
Right. Okay. Orange juice,
funny or not funny?
-Funny.
-Right.
Next. A baseball?
Funny.
Wrong, not funny.
All right. Woodchuck,
funny or not funny floating?
-Funny.
-Extremely funny.
Next, funny
or not funny floating?
Sally Field.
-Not funny.
-Right. Next?
Funny or not funny
floating Sebastian Cabot.
Funny.
Right, extremely funny
but impossible.
Finally, the rules get
a little blurry here, guys.
Christopher Reeves in
Super Man,
funny or not funny floating?
-Not funny.
-Right.
Christopher Reeves in
Monsignor?
-Funny.
-Right.
Now, Christopher Reeves kissing
Michael Caine in Death Trap.
-Oh, funny.
-Right. Finally, Gallagher.
Funny or not funning floating?
-Not funny.
-Extremely unfunny.
Now, we go into
the lightning round.
Cam-bot, put it up on the screen
and Magic Voice,
let's have the password.
[Magic Voice]
The secret password is
"Things which are
Funny Floating."
[bell dings]
Uh, you take your shoe off
with this.
A piece of cheese,
a come-a-long.
Shoe horn.
-Um, right.
-[bell dings]
Uh... you keep meat in this.
-Uh, your mouth?
-[bell dings]
Uh, right.
Um, uh, a juggler.
-Boring things.
-A juggler.
-Uh...
-Hackneyed.
Things at
a Renaissance festival.
Bad actor.
Things you say to a Bishop.
Pass, pass.
Um, flashing light.
-Uh, sale at K-Mart.
-[Crow] Flashing light.
-Buzzer.
-[buzzer sound]
Times Square at midnight.
Things that happen
on movie sets.
-[bell ringing]
-Yeah, that's it.
-Movie set
-[both] Ahh...
Something no human being
ever saw before.
-[Joel] A frogman.
-[Tom] A duck-billed platypus.
[Crow] Scuba gear.
[Joel] Uh, no a piece of lint.
It lives in your stomach.
-[Crow] Lloyd Bridges.
-[Joel] Never mind.
You know it's funny,
one never thinks of the Earth
that way,
as a dying planet
with nothing to give out
but reflected light.
[Joel] Oh, that is romantic.
Think I'll go slit my wrists.
Don't speak so disrespectfully
of the moon.
[Crow] And whatever you do,
don't say anything about Texas.
I've done some of my
best work by moonlight.
[Joel] Boom.
I saw this light very effective.
For navigation?
For any purpose.
Don't underrate it.
Moonlight is potent.
You're speaking of
its effect on men and women?
-[Joel] No tree frogs.
-On women.
I'll need to stop myself.
-Oh. You're immune.
-[Crow] No. I'm Lloyd.
That's the myoon.
Do you still need it?
But did you ever park
in an open convertible
on the cliffs
overlooking the Pacific?
[Joel] And then drive off
laughing maniacally?
[Floyd] ...the moon
hung up there like a lantern.
The blue light from it
walking across the water,
radio playing a nice tune.
-[Tom] Dead body in a trunk.
-Waves wooshing on the beach.
[Tom] bag of quicklime.
No, I, uh...
perhaps unfortunately,
I never had the time
-nor the thought...
-[Crow] Or the quick line.
...to do anything
much beyond my profession.
I don't think you have never
looked at that old moon
except for astronomical reasons.
You're right.
I have
in Rome once,
in Switzerland.
-[Joel] Rome, Switzerland?
-At Lake Lugano.
What a nice stroll.
-Stroll?
-Yes.
Yes, we walked slowly
around the edge of the lake
for two hours.
And never stopped?
No.
[Crow German accent]
Then I measured
the velocity of our walk.
It was lovely there.
Water black like cold coffee,
the moonlight like flecks of
ice cream floating on it.
[Joel] Parking lot
like a Libbyland dinner.
[Crow] Quick, somebody get her
a sandwich.
Oh, but that was so long ago,
another world.
[Tom] Yeah, the Earth.
-Fine scientist I am.
-[Crow] Michael Feinstein.
Daydream.
It's good for you
once in a while.
[Crow] It's wonderful.
I supposed it is, but...
Not now.
[Tom] I'm going to be sick now.
I still say it.
-Say what?
-[all] It.
That moonlight's
effective stuff.
You're quite right.
[Joel] Where do you
want to be in two years?
[Joel] If only...
What effect a double dose
like this
would have in a convertible?
[Crow] Would it rust, crumble?
Have to put it up on blocks.
Skip it.
[explosion]
-Meteorites!
-[Joel] Big ones, too!
-Screamers!
-[Crow] Wow.
[Joel] Hey, cool. That one
looks like my gallstone.
[Crow] Looks like
buttery caramel corn.
Please visit our snack bar.
[Tom] I'll have a Sprite,
please.
-Thanks, Mr. Crow.
-[Crow] Way to go, kid.
[Crow whistling]
[Crow] Looks like poppy cock.
[Tom] Well, who needs a drink?
I know I do.
Boy...
I've been through some
pretty heavy flack in my day,
but that's the worst
I've ever had thrown at me.
[Crow] Yeah, yeah.
We know, in Texas.
Say...
[Crow] That could be a musical.
Maybe somebody don't want us
to get where we aim to get.
[Joel] Yeah, the God of grammar.
Oh, cheer up, Harry.
After what we've been through,
we'll get there all right.
Maybe it'd have been better if
one of them had struck the ship.
At least it would
have been sudden.
[Tom]
Probably wrinkle my shirt.
Quick.
[Crow] Oh, are you
gonna cry now, baby?
-Now, your computation?
-[Joel] Dog ate 'em.
We have to add
12 percent 03 to A16.
Right. 12 percent 03 to A16.
This means we'll have to
rearrange some of the fuel tanks
and all the connections.
[Joel] It would take a rocket
scientist to explain this.
We'll replace these H tanks.
[Crow] And drop
some of the bridesmaids
and order a smaller cake.
Happy now?
Think you can manage
a half ton tank?
Oh, sure.
Down on my ranch, used to throw
a little old thousand pound
steer over my shoulder
every morning.
-[Tom] Then I married her.
-Little bull you were throwing.
[Tom] Get down on the toilet,
you chromo.
Sheesh.
[music playing]
[Joel underwater]
Now let me get this straight.
We go down here and just stare
at stuff again until we fix it.
Is that right?
[Tom underwater] Yep.
[Crow wiseguy voice] That's
blinker light fluid all right.
Want I should check
your muffler belt, too?
All right, Sampson.
Let's see you do your stuff.
Think I was kidding, huh?
-[Tom] Hmm.
-You'll never prove it here.
[Joel] What's a Greek column
doing down here?
Doctor...
can we be quite sure
these proportions are safe?
We never proved them
by experiment.
The mathematical theory
is beyond question.
03 though.
Sometimes it behaves
unpredictably.
Woman's intuition again.
[Joel] Oh, there he goes with
the woman thing again. Great.
Twelve percent 03 to A16.
[Tom] You sunk my battleship!
Thirty-two degrees.
Present position is...
We'll correct course when
we're in pilot flight once more.
All right.
-All ready?
-Ready.
Stand by, everybody.
[Crow] It's going to get nuts.
[Joel] Nice pose.
[noise]
[Joel] Well, she's happy.
[Tom] Got to... hang on...
[Crow] Mrs. Carmichael,
this is your fault.
Oh, Rickyyy...
[Tom] Must... hang... on.
[Joel] Uh, excuse me.
This is my stop.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Joel] That went
rather well I think.
[Crow] I did it.
I'm Mr. Air Speed.
Next needle nose.
We did it all.
Will you repeat that again,
Dr. Hurley?
[Joel] You need one of those
inflatable donuts.
-Are you certain?
-[Joel] Oh, yeah.
No solid food either.
-Scratching irritates it though.
-I see. Thank you.
[Joel] Well, it could be worse.
They are completely
off their course.
[Joel] Those guys could at least
stop shopping at the same store.
Moving with incredible velocity
out into limitless space.
[Crow] Heavy.
I can't understand it.
[Joel] Come on, scatter, guys.
One bullet could get all of us.
[Tom] All right.
Who made the Kool-Aid?
[Joel] Love was
cooling in the mist.
[Tom] It’s 7:15 in deep space,
we’re still on the business end
of a beautiful day.
Got some Bruce Hornsby
and the Range
and then three in a row
from Paula Abdul
[Crow] She awakes
with a hairball
and the worst breath
of the day.
-[Joel] Oh.
-[Crow] Eat an apple.
[Joel] Oh, I'm late honey.
Could you drive me to work?
Oh, we're in space.
[Tom] Better grab
a Hefty bag and start at it.
I'm all right.
[Crow] You know,
one time this happened to me.
I was in a convertible and I...
We're not getting enough oxygen.
[Crow] My lungs are...
well, you know.
[Van Horn] Bill? Bill?
[Joel] Open the window.
[Tom] That was
the worst party ever.
Who invited the Theta Chis?
Dr. Eckstrom.
[Joel] Wake up old guy.
Gale Gordon.
[Crow] Oh, quick, here.
You move his mouth.
I'll do the voice.
Say hello to the folks, Bobby.
[Tom] Hello, folks.
How long has it been since...
[Joel] Hey,
that's rather personal.
How are the others?
[Van Horn] I think everybody's
going to be all right.
-[Crow] Nice stash.
-It must have been days.
Fortunately,
the engines were turned off.
When?
I must have turned the levers
off when I blacked out.
But what speed?
You know the consequences
of a body moving
with unchecked velocity
in free space.
[Crow]
Uh, we're our own grandparents?
So we made a little detour.
Now we got to double back
that last road sign.
Come on.
Let's go to work.
[Joel] Uh, this is a spaceship,
Tom, not a car.
Know what I'm saying?
Remember that blue thing?
Good.
What do you know that's bad
about the big blue thing?
We want to be on it. Dig?
Can't be. The instruments
must have gone crazy.
[Tom] They're
certifiably insane. [chuckles]
I don't think so.
By heading into space,
we've added the Earth's
orbital velocity to our own.
[Crow] And that's bad, right?
We're really moving.
I should say
at least several times
the maximum speed
of your indicator.
[Joel] Not to mention it smells
like a bus station in here.
At least have an approximation
of our position very shortly.
Fuel consumption?
-[Tom] No thanks. I've had...
-Just a moment.
-Doctor?
-What?
I cut in resistances
to raise the scale.
But look.
[Crow] That's very pretty,
Steve, but what does it mean?
[Dr. Eckstrom] Acceleration.
Definite acceleration but...
with the motor's off,
that's impossible unless...
-[Bill] This can't be correct.
-What?
I seem to be getting
a strong reflection of impulse
directly ahead 50,000 miles.
-That explains it.
-Explains what?
[Tom] We've been
looking in a mirror.
I've got to touch all of you.
Duck, duck, duck, goose.
Run.
[Dr. Eckstrom] Unbelievable.
It couldn't be mere chance.
[Joel] Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Keep talking.
-[Joel] Out with it.
-[Tom] Yeah.
[Joel] Out with it.
I don't quite know
how to tell you it's so...
[Joel] Uh-huh.
Spit it out, Brad.
If I could have even
dreamed that it...
[Crow] Cut to the chase.
An incredible
set of circumstances...
-[Joel] Get on with it.
-Precisely at exactly...
[Joel] We're listening.
We're here, hey.
...would carry us unerringly
through space
to our most congenial
planetary neighbor Mars.
-[Joel] We're with you.
-Mars?
[Crow] As in the candy bar?
[Tom] Wow.
Looks just like Art Carney.
[Van Horn] Utterly unbelievable.
[Tom] I suppose they have
a bigger Mars than Texas, huh?
Mars. What do you know?
[Crow]
Well, of all the dumb luck.
I'm sure, no way, Mars.
Here we are in endless space and
you park right in front of Mars.
We must pause
and observe respectfully
while something infinitely
greater assumes control.
[Joel] Heavy.
I believe
this is one of those times.
We should go on, of course.
Our overall
fuel consumption was...
Forty-two percent.
[Joel] And that's good.
A Martian landing, approaching
a planet with atmosphere
is far easier
than the lunar maneuver.
[Joel] And that's good.
We should be betraying
an unprecedented opportunity
to do otherwise.
Then I suggest there's a couple
of little things we might do.
The ship isn't going
to land itself, you know.
-[Joel] And that's bad.
-[Tom] What's he mean by that?
[Crow] Splat.
Mars. [chuckles]
-I'll be darned.
-[Tom] What do you know.
We must first compute
the correct
thrust and fuel mixture
to comply with
anticipated conditions.
[Joel] And then we dream.
[Van Horn] ...twelve thousand
five hundred miles an hour.
Oxygen at surface level,
15 percent.
Prepare to change
the parallel course
-at distance 1,500 miles.
-[Joel] Check.
[Crow] And wipe that
dopey grin off your face.
I've located it.
-Located what?
-[Tom] Our clean shorts.
Well, where are they?
Here. Take a look.
[Joel] Hey, Tex, what do you say
we blast 'em just for fun?
[Tom chuckles]
For old times’ sake.
[William] What do you know
about that?
[Tom] Well, I know
the little one's the moon.
Is it all right to call Texas
a mere speck now?
[Joel]
Man, I never liked that guy.
[Crow] Now Linus is different.
His hair is kind of crazy.
You draw 'em like this.
At 50 miles altitude, we will
execute a turn of 90 degrees,
bringing the rocket
into the landing position.
[Joel] Could you sharpen this?
Since the gravitational
attraction to Mars
is only half as powerful
as that of Earth,
a thrust of 1200 tons will be
sufficient to make the landing.
-Fuel?
-Hydrogen and oxygen plus A12.
[Tom] That's my favorite blend.
Water, shaken not stirred.
-[Joel inhales]
-One hundred seventy miles.
[Tom] He's getting a facial.
[Crow] His pores are opening.
[Harry] Sixty-five.
[Joel] Oh, that one
looks kind of like a horsey.
Hey, that one looks like
our friend, Dana.
-Sixty.
-[Joel] Yeah, I can see too.
Looks like Dana
and I see the horsey. It's neat.
[Dr. Eckstrom] Stand by to turn.
Fifty.
Turn.
[Crow] Coming about. Hard alee.
Watch the boom.
I see the great white.
[Tom] Queequeg.
[buzzing]
[Joel]
They're in the spin cycle.
Must add fabric softener.
Socks are sticking to the side.
[Crow coughing]
[Crow] Hey,
we're half a bubble off plumb.
[Tom] Whoa.
[Joel exhales in relief]
Ninety-degree turn completed.
Reduce power.
[Crow] You know,
once I was on a Tilt A Whirl.
[Joel, Tom] Shut up.
[Crow] Goodnight.
[Joel] Reverse stock footage
come in for landing mode.
Altitude 40 miles,
38 miles.
I only hope
the light holds out.
It's getting dark down below.
[Tom]
My chin looks great in here.
[Joel] Love me.
Prepare to increase thrust
at an altitude 15 miles.
[Crow] We'll park it
by the Chrysler.
[thrusting sound]
It's getting darker rapidly.
As far as I can make out, the
terrain is suitable for landing.
[Tom] It's a good thing
because we're landing.
Five miles,
20,000 feet, 18,000.
Thrust at 1,250 tons.
Standby to increase power.
Fifteen thousand.
[Crow] Bottles of beer
on the wall.
-[Harry] Twelve thousand.
-Bottles of beer on the wall.
-[Harry] Ten thousand.
Eight thousand, 7000, 6000.
We're losing altitude too fast.
Increase thrust at 3,000 tons.
[Joel] Uh, that's this thing,
right? Got it.
Four thousand feet.
Three thousand.
[Bill] Two thousand feet.
Reduce thrust slowly
to 1,250 tons.
[Tom] Third floor,
notions, ready to wear.
[Bill] One thousand.
Five hundred.
[Joel] Oh, look.
There's a gantry on space.
[Tom] First floor.
[Crow]
Like they don't even care.
Nice work, Floyd.
[Crow] Oh, thank you, Andy.
Ooh, what a fine landing. Yes.
[thunder]
Mars extending us a welcome.
[Tom German accent]
Extending us a welcome.
We'll prepare to disembark
first thing in the morning.
In the meantime, we can rest
and get our equipment ready.
Well, that's what
I've been waiting for.
[Tom] I love equipment.
I've been itching
to get into one of these things.
-[Tom] It's my grandma's skin.
-Sorry to disappoint you, Bill.
We have atmosphere here.
-We won't need pressure suits.
-[Tom] Oh, man.
Which works greatly
in our favor, too.
[Tom] I don't get
to have any fun.
We can accomplish
so much more unencumbered.
As far as equipment's concerned,
we'll take oxygen masks,
camera, paraphernalia.
What about data
for the return trip?
[Crow] Yes, yes.
Data for the return trip too.
Yes, of course. You're right.
We have so little time here.
Such an opportunity.
Let's think about that
for a little while.
[Joel] Let's turn in
for the night...
and full day.
[theme music playing]
[Joel] Come on
and march in double time.
[Tom] Come on
[Joel] Let's sing a song
by Michael Feinstein.
[Tom] Sing a song
-[Joel] Sound off.
-[Tom] One, two.
[Joel] Sound off.
[all] Three, four,
clap on, clap off,
the clapper.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Crow] We thought
it would be funny
if we blackened
the eyepieces on his binoculars.
Let's see what
Walt Disney thinks.
Look at
the rock formation there.
[Joel] Looks like Arizona to me.
-Notice the abundant coloration?
-[Crow] Just more the same.
...yellow, black.
[Joel] Raspberry red,
lemon yellow, orange orange.
Manganese, copper, nickel,
pitch blend.
[Tom] Sphagnum,
zircon, molybdenum,
sternum, aquarium, colitis.
[man in the middle] Are you
staking out a claim here?
Just making sure
we can find our way back.
[Joel] You talking to me?
[Tom] My hose
goes right into my sternum.
[Joel]
Uh, who brought the sandwiches.
[Crow] Uh, sandwiches?
[Tom, Crow, Joel] ♪ Valderi,
Valdera, Valderi, Valdera ♪
[Tom] Ahh, Ricky.
[Tom, Crow, Joel humming a song]
[Crow] Okay, if we don't find
a bush or a tree
in the next two miles,
well, just go anywhere.
[Tom, Crow, Joel] ♪ Valderi,
Valdera, Valderi, Valdera ♪
[Tom chuckles]
[Tom, Crow, Joel spitting]
All we've seen so far is
rock and sand, sand and rocks.
[Joel] You said it.
I wonder when we're going to run
across some of these Martians.
From what I read,
they've got pale faces
and pinheads and fishy eyes.
[Crow] I heard that
said about Texans too.
[Tom] What did he say?
Ah, forget it.
Let's go collect some maggots.
[Joel] Things on Mars
are pretty bad.
[Tom] Things on Mars
I'm starting to like
the Rockford Dad.
[Crow] Starting to like
[Joel] This must be
the creamy nugget center...
of a Mars.
[Joel] Hey look, guys.
There's the Statue of Liberty.
And there's James Franciscus
and Charlton Heston.
You did it. You finally did it.
Damn you all to hell.
[Tom] Hey, look at
all the driftwood.
We could make
cool stuff out of this.
[Crow] Gosh, those Stuckys
are everywhere.
[Joel] All right.
Who wants a nut log anybody?
I'm going to get
some roasted chicken.
[Tom] They got onion rings here?
-[Joel] He wants onion rings.
-[Tom] Get me a loaf for myself.
[Crow] I want a toy.
Hey, what kind of lens
you got in that camera there?
[Joel] Well, it's neat
and all but I'm tired.
[Tom] Wow.
This Bart Simpson stuff
is everywhere.
Let's not spend
all our money here.
We're only
on the outskirts of town.
[Crow] Yeah, there's
a gas station near my house
-that sells this junk.
-[clank]
[Joel] Sounds like your head,
Texan.
[Crow] Got salt shakers this big
in Texas, country boy?
[Dr. Eckstrom]
At least the equal of Earth.
[Joel] Or buy it from Pier 1.
[Van Horn] Do you think that
a complex organized society
existed here once?
[Dr. Eckstrom]
Yes, and from all indications,
thousands of years ago.
I wonder how it happened.
[Tom] Billions and billions
of years ago.
[Harry] But then it would have
created a depression
like a moon crater.
[Dr. Eckstrom] No.
This wasn't caused by a meteor.
[Crow]
This was no boating accident.
...blast effect
coupled with intense heat.
[Joel] I think it
was street gangs.
[Tom] I think it was
a drive-by shooting.
-[Tom] Yeah.
-[Joel] Yeah.
[Crow] Hey, look,
a big cow cream pitcher.
[Joel] My grandfather
went to Mars
and all I got was this
crummy T-shirt.
[Tom] That looks like
an Evinrude to me.
[Crow] Oh, look it's a Theremin.
You'd better stop.
Radioactivity
is at the danger level.
[Joel] And that's a bad thing.
[Crow] Right.
[Dr. Eckstrom] Ironic, isn't it?
The mind of man
wherever you encounter it,
Earth or Mars.
[Crow snoring]
The highest attainment
of human intellect...
[Crow coughing]
[Joel] Sorry.
[Crow] You can't swing
a dead cat
without hitting
one of his boring speeches.
...ruined like this.
[Floyd] Don't you think we ought
start back for the ship?
[William] I agree to that.
We're neither prepared nor
equipped for any stay here.
[Dr. Eckstrom] We have supplies
for several days.
Let's use this precious time
as effectively as we can.
[Crow] Let's all take a nap.
[Van Horn] Dr. Eckstrom,
a day here is more valuable
than years of research on Earth.
[Floyd] Well, okay
then let's get going.
[Tom] Okay, people.
Half an hour and we'll meet
at the Hot Sands, all right?
[Joel] And there
on the handle was a hook.
[Dr. Eckstrom] What a lesson
here for our world.
One blast...
[Joel] Now, what did we
learn today, Jim?
-[Crow] Not to steal.
-[Tom] That was yesterday.
[Van Horn] Could there
have been any survivors?
[Dr. Eckstrom] I should hate
to think so.
-[Crow] What-- Line please.
-[Joel] Line.
[Tom] Line.
We still don't know all the
genetic effects of radiation,
but that it will
produce mutation,
malformaties
disfigurements, blindness.
That much we're sure of
from research.
A blast like this...
I should hate to think
that any survived.
[Joel] Now goodnight, everybody.
[Harry] Why don't you
try to get some rest.
[William] If I ever
get back to Texas,
I'll know better
than to leave again.
[Crow] Oh, shut up.
Ever since we left,
all that's been out of you
is Texas this and Texas that.
Well, listen, bub.
I've been to Texas
and it's not all that great!
Sheesh! I'm leaving.
[Joel] We better
get out of here. I'll carry you.
[Tom] It was a dark...
What do you guys
want to do with your life?
What are your dreams?
I mean, where do you
want to be in two years?
Beauty walks the razor's edge.
Someday I'll make it mine.
[Tom] Bless the beasts
and the children.
Why do birds suddenly appear
every time you walk near?
All I want is a tall ship
and a star to sail her by.
[Tom] Oz never did give
nothing to the Tin Man.
One is the loneliest number
that you'll ever do.
I dreamed I saw
Joe Hill last night.
[Tom] Half-breed.
That's all I ever heard.
We had joy, we had fun,
we had seasons in the sun.
But the stars that we reached
were just starfish on the beach.
[Tom] Dames like this
always got beer around.
What?
[Tom] Oh, I mean...
filled with mangled cream
and amber
I will drain that classic aim
such hilarious visions clamber.
-Oh.
-[Joel] Oh.
[Crow] Yeah.
Hey, there's a ship out there.
Who said that?
I did.
[Tom] Oh, that's beautiful.
[Crow] No, no, no. There's...
really, there's a ship outside.
It just goes on like that?
No.
Outside, there's a ship outside.
[Tom] Oh, you mean
mean outside the bounds
of earthly restraints.
No, no! Out there!
See look!
-[Joel] Yikes. He's right.
-[Tom] There's a ship out there.
Hey, Cam-bot,
give me a rocket number 9.
I need an exterior to the ship.
Let's go, you guys.
[Joel] There's somebody
outside the ship,
-and they're trying to hail us.
-[Tom] Huh?
Check it out on
the Hexfield Viewscreen.
Hello, puny Earthling.
[Tom] Oh hi. I think
she's talking to Joel.
I've come these many light years
to find you and now,
you and your daughter
are doomed.
[Crow] Maybe she's
talking about Gypsy, Joel.
You and your daughter
will never escape
the power of the dark one.
[Joel] Dark one?
Doug Warren?
I haven't seen him
since high school.
Dark one.
I don't know any dark one.
You dare to mock me?
See if you can mock me
in the room of questions.
Uh, Joel, who is she
and what the heck does she mean?
Just let me handle this.
I know how to talk
to these space vixens.
Uh, I could never
give into your... demands.
You'll never get
any satisfaction out of me.
Not even a little?
No, I...
God she's ugly.
Okay, well then got to go.
Bye-bye.
-Wait, wait.
-[speaks alien language]
Wait, wait, wait. Joel.
Maybe she can help us
get back down to Earth.
Yeah.
Can you rescue us or help us?
To Earth? I don't know.
What does it look like?
We have to get down to Earth.
How nice for you.
Got to go. Ciao. Bye-bye.
[speaks alien language]
-I live to serve you.
-Bye-bye.
-[Crow] Whoa, whoa.
-[Tom] Hey!
Oh, man.
[Tom] What a strange woman.
Kind of makes you think,
though, doesn't it?
[Joel, Crow] Yeah.
Guess you don't have to be
a rocket scientist
to pilot a rocketship.
Well, at least we've still
got each other, you guys.
Yeah. No matter where
I serve my guests,
it seems they like
the kitchen best.
Yeah. And if you don't believe
the dead come back to life,
you should see this place
around quitting time.
-[Crow laughs]
-Yeah.
It's a nice day
for a white wedding.
We got commercial sign.
Hey, I'm moved.
Who said that?
[Tom] Was that Blake?
Yeats perhaps, or Rod McKuen?
Hmm.
[music playing]
[Joel] You don't have to be
crazy to work here, but help.
[Crow chuckles]
[Tom] Meanwhile,
here in the day for night scene.
It'd be a good place
for a water slide over there,
don't you think?
[Crow] I'm going to go out
and discover a new race
and show 'em all.
This is my side of the mountain.
I'll show those guys.
I'll live in a tree.
Yeah, that's great.
Make boomerangs.
[Joel] Snuggle close, friend.
[Crow] I'll show 'em.
[Joel] I'm kind of tired.
[Tom] Oh, man.
Either I'm high or there's about
50 Martian dudes down there.
Oh, man, game over.
Oh, I got to lay off the butane.
[Joel] Hey, they're
shooting 2001 down there.
[William] Bill, Floyd,
Dr. Eckstrom.
[Crow] Reese... Youngblood.
[Tom] Maybe I'm crazy,
but I just saw our ancestors
and they're walking erect.
[Crow] You squirting glue
in that mask?
It wasn't a nightmare.
I haven't slept at all.
-I tell you I saw them!
-Where?
Right out there.
And when I yelled,
they disappeared.
All right. Let's go see.
[Joel] It was the cast of
Chorus Line, I swear.
[Crow] Let's all run like fools
toward the danger!
[Tom] Serpentine everybody!
Incoming wounded!
[Joel]
I know they're around here.
Right here.
When they heard me,
they disappeared in there.
[Joel] Yeah, and you were there
and you, and you and everybody.
[William]
It don't take a Navajo
to figure out what caused these.
[Crow] Yeah,
and we're rocket scientists.
[William] Now maybe you'll
agree to return to the ship.
[Joel] Oh, come on sissy pants.
...kind of creatures they are.
[Tom]
Well, they definitely have feet.
[Harry] We don't know
how many there are?
And suppose they're hostile,
with one rifle and a pistol.
We won't have a prayer.
[Dr. Eckstrom] That's the chance
we have to take.
[Joel] And you're taking it.
[Dr. Eckstrom] You wait here.
I'm going ahead.
[William] This kind of thing is
just my meat.
Mind if I come along?
-[Dr. Eckstrom] Thank you.
-I'm with you, Doctor.
[Dr. Eckstrom] You three stay.
I'll have to make that an order.
Come on, Bill.
[Crow] Yeah, let's go kill
something we don't understand.
[Tom] I'm bringing my pool cue
in case they start
ranking on our women.
[Joel] Does anybody
got any lines?
[Crow] Well, we'll just wait
here then, shall we?
Right.
[Joel] We could play Pictionary.
Oh, I know,
I spy with my little eye.
Wait.
They're there.
There they go. Wait.
No, no, don't...
don't shoot too high.
Lead them on.
[all] Help! I've fallen
and I can't get up.
[Tom] I'm having chest pains.
[Joel, Tom, Crow]
Boom chaka laka...
[Joel] You know,
she's not half bad.
Wonder if she'd
like to evolve up.
She's moving up
in the food chain in my eyes,
if you know what I mean.
[Crow] Hello, Federal.
[Joel] Now we've
never met before, have we?
[screaming]
[Tom] No, it's okay.
He won't tell another story.
I promise.
[Joel] Oh my goodness.
[Joel] Geez, it's an
entire race of mimes.
We got to get back
and warn Earth.
[Crow] Oh, yuck,
unfortunate skin.
[Joel] Boom chaka laka...
Atomic Age...
to Stone Age.
[Tom] In less than
30 minutes guaranteed.
[Tom] Message coming in, sir!
Bill!
[Tom] They got rocks that big
in Texas, Bill?
[Crow] Thank you,
but I already have one of those.
[Joel] Sorry to have interrupted
your production of the lottery.
[Tom] Thanks for the rocks.
Here's some bullets for you.
[gunshots]
[Crow] Here's some more.
[Joel] I guess I embarrassed
them in front of their chicks.
[Joel, Tom] Boom chaka laka...
[Crow mumbles something]
[Tom] ♪ Valderi, Valdera,
Valderi, Valdera ♪
[Crow] Lead him on.
Don't throw too hard.
Well. Hey, Steve,
how'd everything go?
[Van Horn] Dr. Eckstrom.
[Joel] Big... mean... guy...
throw rock down... over there.
[Floyd] Where's Bill?
[Joel] I brought back
a souvenir.
[Crow] Sounds like...
um... sounds like fall, fall,
tall, tall down, tall down.
[Joel] You move his head.
I'll do the voice.
[Floyd] Murdering savages.
[Dr. Eckstrom] No, Floyd.
They are crazed...
[Joel] Brother, he's dying
and he's still giving speeches.
-[Dr. Eckstrom mumbles]
-[Van Horn] Don't talk anymore.
[Dr. Eckstrom] You must
get back to Earth.
Tell them what we found.
Maybe this will...
[Crow] Will... Will what?
Fall down?
Play dead? What?
[Joel] Now what do we do?
He's got the keys.
Thanks. We've got plenty.
[Joel, Tom, Crow]
Boom chaka laka...
[Joel, Tom, Crow] ♪ Valderi,
Valdera, Valderi, Valdera ♪
[Joel, Tom, Crow]
Boom chaka laka...
[Tom] ♪ Valderi, Valdera,
Valderi, Valdera ♪
[Joel] Well, at least he
hasn't been hit by a rock yet.
[Tom] Oh. Good shot.
[Joel] That's just my spine,
sir.
[Crow] Come back
and you'll get more of the same.
[Joel] Val... deri...
Val... dera...
[Crow] Take that.
[Joel] Well, that
could have gone better.
-[Tom] Help, Mr. Wizard.
-[Crow] Nonsense.
[Joel] Run away.
Run away.
[Tom] I don't want to be
an astronaut anymore.
[Joel] Oh, Scooby, we got to
get out of here, Scooby.
[Crow German accent] Drizzle,
drazzle, drazzle, drome,
Time for this one to come home.
Ho ho.
[theme music playing]
[Joel] Where do
you want to be in two years?
I wish Harry were able to help.
It's impossible to get
a precise result without radar.
You have done a wonderful job.
We should have
fuel enough for landing.
When we feel
the Earth's gravity?
As soon as there's
an increase in speed.
According to elapsed time
and velocity chart,
almost any minute now.
But without a check
from Harry, it's...
I know we're in a tight spot.
[Crow] Where are we going
to cash a check out here?
[Joel]
Lloyd, you're flying a rocket,
not balancing
the household budget.
Get with it.
[Tom] Okay, now, uh,
where did he put the charts?
Go ugh!
There. All better.
Any sign of increase in speed?
Not yet.
[Crow] How's the plot doing?
You know, you're a pretty
swell girl, Lisa.
[Joel] Oh, now that everyone's
dead I'm a pretty swell girl.
I'm not Dr. Van Horn anymore?
No. Just Lisa.
Doing her job.
No. I don't
see it that way at all.
I see a woman sweet, gentle.
[Crow] And when I
get back to Earth,
I'm going to call this girl,
but in the meantime,
love the one you're with.
Somehow, no.
But I am, you know,
the same I mean.
Well, maybe I've
changed then but...
I feel I've... I've never
known you before.
Will you... do something for me,
please?
Sure. What?
Say my name the way
you did a moment ago.
[Crow] Cookie pants?
Lisa.
[Tom] Oh, Lisa.
[Crow] Hey, Mr. Douglas, I see
you're doing some shooshin'.
RXM calling BWS.
[Joel] What's the matter, boy?
Dream about rabbits?
Fire in Dead Rock Canyon?
Come in, DWS.
[Crow] Oh, ick. She's swabbing
him with a jock strap.
They won't answer.
-They will never answer.
-Of course they will.
Speed's increasing.
We're going to make it.
Shut off the fuel.
[Joel] All right.
[Tom] Oh, yeah.
[Joel] Uh, about that fuel,
Lloyd.
[Tom] Well, the good news is
that we won't make a big
explosion when we hit the Earth.
[chuckles]
[Crow] Heh.
[Crow] Kimmie, honey,
where'd you put the extra fuel?
I'm sorry.
-I wish I could help.
-[Tom] Tuck him in, Joel.
You heard what Floyd said.
Everything will be all right.
About the fuel...
we lost so much.
We'll have enough
for a landing.
[Tom] He was thirsty,
he drank it.
[Crow] Well, this should really
test Lloyd's sunny disposition.
How are we doing?
-Not so good.
-Why? What's the matter?
Everything's worked out
so far right in the nose.
We haven't got
enough fuel for a landing.
[Tom] Have enough
fuel for a crash?
Not even for the approach.
But the motors
were functioning perfectly
before I shut them off.
At one tenth capacity.
[crying] I'm sorry.
It's all my fault.
Maybe it's only the instruments.
[Tom] Just keep telling
yourself that, Lloyd.
It's hopeless.
[Joel] So much for the
power of positive thinking,
huh, Lloyd?
[Crow] Could they steer it
into a willow tree or something?
All of Dr. Eckstrom's work
in vain.
[Tom] His work?
Uh, what about your life?
Now the world will never know
the terrible truth we learned.
No.
Maybe there's still a chance.
We must be close enough
for short wave.
Try to contact the base.
If we only could.
We must report everything.
Tell them as much as we can,
what we saw,
the mistakes that we made.
[Crow] Okay. Story so far -
we got lost, flew to Phoenix,
got attacked,
we're going to die.
[Joel] Doomed spaceship
to Earth.
Doomed spaceship to Earth.
-Dr. Fleming?
-Yes?
The radio control room
just called.
They've contacted the RXM.
[Joel] There's a Mister...
Oh my God, my hair
is on fire on line one, sir.
You know, we really should have
gotten adjoining offices.
This is really quite a long walk
when you think about it.
[Tom] I think Rudy's.
[Joel]
Going to Rudy's? Yeah, okay.
There's too much interference.
We've got to use these, Doctor.
[Crow]
What? I can't see a thing.
[Tom] Is this Strauss?
BWS, Fleming speaking.
Calling RXM.
Come in, RXM.
[Crow] Help.
Repeat that again,
please, Dr. Van Horn.
-[Crow] I said...
-[Joel, Tom, Crow] Help!
-[Crow] H-E-L-P...
-[Tom] It's in Greek.
-[Crow] ...pronounced
-[all] Help!
What about Dr. Eckstrom?
[Joel] Uh, door nail,
daisies, worm food,
thrown in the sponge.
How many feet under?
Joined who?
[Tom] Ooh.
[Crow] Why the long face?
[Joel] But did he say
he loved me?
[Tom] Aw.
[Joel] My life's over, friends.
Come on. Spread out...
Oh, what the hell.
[Crow sniffling]
[Crow crying]
[Joel] I thought worm food
was a bit strong, Lloyd.
Where do you want to be
in two years?
Uh, I mean two minutes?
Floyd, hold me.
Hold me tight.
[Crow] If I held you any
tighter, I'd be in back of you.
[Tom imitates drum sound]
I'm sorry that
we haven't had any time,
that we didn't meet and know
each other the way we...
[Joel] Hey, we've got the
rest of our lives together.
-Oh, yes, yes.
-Don't.
We can say that time's
behind us.
-We've had years together.
-Yes.
I can tell you what a thousand
wonderful hours we spent
together because
I feel we would have.
[Tom]
It's all community service.
There's not that much difference
between the future and the past.
[Joel] You are high.
Shouldn't we wake him?
[Crow] Why? So he can experience
his own fiery death?
[Joel] Get your shoes on, honey.
We're about to die.
[Floyd] Try not to be afraid.
Floyd...
I'm not afraid anymore.
[Tom] Neither am I.
Something happened like a great
wave carrying us home,
bearing us, protecting us.
[Joel] Uh, where's...
[Tom] Woohoo.
[explosion]
[Joel] We scraped off
the runway, sir.
[man] The men from the news
syndicates are still waiting.
[Fleming]
All right. Let them come in.
[Joel] [bong]
[Tom] Keep it down, boys.
Dr. Fleming. The pilot and crew
of flight 19
International Airlines
observed a strange object
falling over Nova Scotia.
[Joel] Those were my friends.
[man with mustache]
It could have been the RXM.
My office has been
getting the same story
over the wires for hours.
We know the RXM
had been overdue a long time.
Is there any connection, doctor?
[Crow] Why doctor,
you've been crying.
As yet, there has been
no confirmation, but...
yes, I believe
there is a connection.
Then they all perished
in the crash.
No. Two were lost earlier.
But the flight must
be considered a failure.
[Joel] -Uh-oh.
-A failure?
-Every point of our...
-[Joel] Get out!
It has proven that interspace
travel is not only possible,
but practical.
[Crow] And enjoyable
for all members of the family.
Oh, there will be carnage.
[Fleming] ...which may well mean
the salvation of our own world.
No, gentlemen,
the flight of the RXM
was not a failure.
[Joel] But a resounding success.
Tomorrow we start construction
of RXM2.
[Joel] Oh, no, not again.
Let's get out of here.
-[Tom] Oh, look.
-[Joel] A rotten day.
Somebody stole my Woody.
[Crow] Oh, man.
What a crappy day.
Boy. Nothing more depressing
than being locked in a capsule
watching a movie about
people dying in a capsule.
Yeah, why don't
you just show us Marooned?
We couldn't get it.
Well, you wouldn't show terror
at 30,000 feet in an airplane,
would you?
[both] No.
Yeah, and you wouldn't show
Das Boot on a submarine,
would you?
Yeah, and you wouldn't show
a Burt Reynolds movie
to prisoners, would you?
Yeah, and you wouldn't show
Breakfast at Tiffany's
at a jewelry store.
-[all] Huh?
-There!
Oh, owie, owie, owie, owie,
owie, owie, owie, owie!
Don't you have some mail
to read, frog blossom?
Frog blossom?
Geez, just say so.
They're right here.
Cam-bot, let's put this one up
on the screen. It's visual.
Dear Joel, let me start off
by saying I love your show.
But I think it is time
to get some new robots.
[Crow, Tom] Hey.
[Joel] To aid you
and your guests in your quest
to find the dumbest
sci-fi movie ever made.
Sure Cam-bot, Tom, Gypsy,
Tom Servo and Crow are great,
but you need more guys
to fill up the empty seats
in front of the theater.
[Tom] Oh, I don't think so.
Well, I guess that's it.
Looks like you can bring us
down, Frank.
-Okay, sure.
-No, you idiot!
Tell them what you thought
about the experiment.
Uh, uh, that'll be $5.50.
Pull ahead, please.
Oh, never mind.
Until next time, Joely cakes.
All right, Frank,
push the button.
Oh, what did I do?
It's okay. Hit shift, clear.
Okay, now hit the button.
-This one?
-That one.
-This one!
Sorry. He's new.
[theme music playing]